# Ben McAllister

Software Developer



Agile developer with 3+ years of experience in the point of sale industry, determined to build software solutions based on solid practices and robust designs in any market segment. Currently managing code deployments that reach 100,000+ users using skills in Android and iOS. Background in architecture design, data structures, functional programming, parallel computing, and testing.

# Experience

#### 365 Retail Markets

#### Android, iOS

Mobile Developer

Apr 2021 - Present

- Building software for products like PicoMarket/PicoCooler and 365Pay.
- Designing architecture for cross-company API interfaces.
- Managing multiple Git repositories and CI/CD pipelines.
- Overseeing production issues and triaging solutions.
- Refactoring UI to simplify user flows and increase user retention.

Junior Mobile Developer

Aug 2019 - Apr 2021

- Built out software distribution system for timely terminal updates and status events.
- Created customer facing provisioning interface to increase product scalability.

Mobile Development Intern

May 2019 - Aug 2019

- Developed leading kiosks and mobile apps for MicroMarket vending services.
- Worked within a small team and with other companies to integrate international projects.

### University of Michigan

Java, C++, x86 Assembly

Grader

Jun 2018 - May 2019

- Worked alongside professors in grading students in high level computer science courses.
- Graded for Java Programming, Data Structures and Algorithm Analysis, and others.

#### Education

#### University of Michigan - Dearborn

Sep 2017 - Dec 2019

Bachelor of Science in Software Engineering (GPA 3.91).

#### Oakland Community College

Sep 2014 - May 2017

Associate in Applied Science degree in Software Engineering (GPA 3.75).

Associate in Applied Science degree in Technological Sciences (GPA 3.75).

## Skills

Kotlin/Java
Native Android/iOS
SQL (MySQL/SQLite)
React-Native
AWS
Google Firebase
Python
C++
C#

- TypeScript/JavaScript - Spring (Kotlin/Java) - Agile Development - React - Express (Node.js) - Algorithm Analysis

- Azure DevOps -  $\mathrm{HTML/CSS}$  -  $\mathrm{L\!\!^{A}T_{\!\!E}\!X}$ 

# **Additional Projects**

- Minesweeper AI: Algorithm that uses linear algebra to solve minesweeper (Java).
- <u>C++ Code Smell Visualization</u>: Script that identifies unsound C++ code (Python).
- <u>Dungeon Board</u>: Standalone application for board games that displays on another screen with dynamic areas hidden or multiple image layers (Java).
- **PushPoint**: App that serves ads using geofencing (Android/Firebase/Java/JavaScript).